<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vSphere on Chris Neales Blog</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/vsphere/</link><description>Recent content in vSphere on Chris Neales Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/vsphere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Newly created vsphere.local SSO user gets username/password error</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-05-22-newuserfail/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-05-22-newuserfail/</guid><description>I was recently creating new users in vsphere.local in a lab environment. When I came to test logging in I got &amp;ldquo;invalid username/password&amp;rdquo; from the web-client.
Hmm odd. So I went back in and checked the username was spelt correctly and reset the password typing slowly.
Back out. Tried login again&amp;hellip;.same error. Ok maybe I&amp;rsquo;m being really fat fingered. Nope I typed the password into a notepad and it was correct.</description></item><item><title>Reasons to upgrade NSX 6.0/6.1 to 6.2</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-04-18-reasonstoupgradensx6.0-part1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-04-18-reasonstoupgradensx6.0-part1/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank my colleague Robbie Hancock https://twitter.com/blobbieh for teasing out the troubleshooting/identification of problem steps.
**Symptom** : If you have VMs that
Stop responding to network requests Cannot ping a VM from another VM or ESG Do not have entries in their ARP table Initiating a ping from the affected VM to ESG or another VM and traffic resumes (ARP table entry appears) After an amount if inactivity, the problem returns&amp;hellip;.</description></item><item><title>vExpert - Why go for it?</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-10-07-vexpert-why-bother/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-10-07-vexpert-why-bother/</guid><description>I was driving home Friday night when my phone bleeped to tell me a colleague had DM&amp;rsquo;d me on Twitter. I made a mental note to check when I got home.
After a couple of hours spent building MetalBeard out of Lego I remembered and read it.
&amp;ldquo;Congratulations vExpert&amp;rdquo; it said. I checked the VMware blog and found this http://blogs.vmware.com/vmtn/2014/10/vexpert-2014-q3-announcement.html#src=vmw_so_vex_cneal_850
I was very pleased that my efforts evangelising around virtualisation and in particular VMware had been recognised.</description></item><item><title>Watchlist - Mobile app to monitor hosts and VMS in vSphere</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-06-09-watchlist-mobile-app-to-monitor-hosts-and-vms-in-vsphere/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-06-09-watchlist-mobile-app-to-monitor-hosts-and-vms-in-vsphere/</guid><description>Whilst searching around I spotted an app is never used from VMware in the Play store.
It&amp;rsquo;s called Watchlist and it gives you simple monitoring and visibility of selected Hosts and VMs that you choose from your standalone host or vCenter instance. You can easily view their statuses:
And see the console of a VM, see what resources it is using and also stop/start/reset it.
I just restarted one of my virtual hosts and watched it boot in the console.</description></item></channel></rss>