<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMware on Chris Neales Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/vmware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMware on Chris Neales Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VCIX-NV Exam Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-11-21-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-11-21-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</guid>
      <description>This is a post in two parts, first the exam experience, second a few pondering on VMware Education&amp;rsquo;s current trajectory.
The Day Itself Here in the UK there are only 3, I believe, VCAP accredited test centres. I hopped on a train across to Leeds, that ended up being delayed and I only had time for a coffee and sandiwch before having to get started. Moral here is give yourself plenty of time to get to your chosen test centre and if possible/affordable, go the night before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerCLI running in a Docker Container on Photon OS in under 10 minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-11-07-docker-powerclicore-sub10mins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-11-07-docker-powerclicore-sub10mins/</guid>
      <description>I needed a utility VM to run a PowerCLI script as a scheduled task.
I set out to do this using Windows but stopped as VMware&amp;rsquo;s Geniuses had just released the PowerCLIcore Fling. This instantly made me think, smaller footprint, quicker to deploy, zero OS license cost&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;No Brainer really
To recreate this all you need is something to host your Photon VM. Standalone ESXi host or VMWorkstation.
Oh and a VCSA/ESXi to connect to (v5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newly created vsphere.local SSO user gets username/password error</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-05-22-newuserfail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-05-22-newuserfail/</guid>
      <description>I was recently creating new users in vsphere.local in a lab environment. When I came to test logging in I got &amp;ldquo;invalid username/password&amp;rdquo; from the web-client.
Hmm odd. So I went back in and checked the username was spelt correctly and reset the password typing slowly.
Back out. Tried login again&amp;hellip;.same error. Ok maybe I&amp;rsquo;m being really fat fingered. Nope I typed the password into a notepad and it was correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reasons to upgrade NSX 6.0/6.1 to 6.2</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-04-18-reasonstoupgradensx6.0-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-04-18-reasonstoupgradensx6.0-part1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank my colleague Robbie Hancock https://twitter.com/blobbieh for teasing out the troubleshooting/identification of problem steps.
If you have VMs that
Stop responding to network requests Cannot ping a VM from another VM or ESG Do not have entries in their ARP table Initiating a ping from the affected VM to ESG or another VM and traffic resumes (ARP table entry appears) After an amount if inactivity, the problem returns&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere vApps unaffected by Back to 28 Vulnerability (CVE-2015-8370)</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-12-20-grub-back-to-28-doesnt-affect-vmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-12-20-grub-back-to-28-doesnt-affect-vmware/</guid>
      <description>Recently Hector Marco and Ismael Ripoll discovered a vulnerability in common Linux bootloader GRUB.
It affects GRUB2 specifically and was introduced into that version in 2009
http://hmarco.org/bugs/CVE-2015-8370-Grub2-authentication-bypass.html
https://web.nvd.nist.gov/view/vuln/detail?vulnId=CVE-2015-8370
However it doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect the original GRUB.
I was concerned about the Virtual Appliances we were running in one of our environments.
VCSA - vCenter Server Appliance 5.5 Update 2e | 16 APR 2015| Build 2646489 vRealize Log Insight 3.0 GA Build 3021606 VROPS 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi and AD Part 2 Joining a Domain without Domain Admin Privileges</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-12-13-esxi-and-ad-part-2-joining-a-domain-without-domain-admin-privileges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-12-13-esxi-and-ad-part-2-joining-a-domain-without-domain-admin-privileges/</guid>
      <description>Problem You need to join an ESXi host to AD but you do not have Domain Admins. Your AD team ask what rights ESXi requires and you can&amp;rsquo;t tell them VMware Support give you a stock &amp;ldquo;You must have Domain Admins&amp;rdquo; reply to a support call. Solution Delegate the rights as per the following Microsoft KB Article https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/kb/932455 &amp;hellip;yes I know it&amp;rsquo;s for 2003 but AD hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed that much since then&amp;hellip;shhh don&amp;rsquo;t tell!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld - Finally at the Frontier!</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-10-12-vmworld-finally-at-the-frontier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-10-12-vmworld-finally-at-the-frontier/</guid>
      <description>I am here. I&amp;rsquo;m in Barcelona. Tomorrow I will be attending the partner day activities and following that such amazing things as the vExpert party!
I lie here in my Chintz Pink Hotel (Picture attached at the end) marvelling that this has actually come off.
I have spent 2-3 weeks sorting this out. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into details but suffice to say the red tape I&amp;rsquo;ve had to negotiate has involved things that, in peace-time, no person should have to endure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vExpert - Why go for it?</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-10-07-vexpert-why-bother/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-10-07-vexpert-why-bother/</guid>
      <description>I was driving home Friday night when my phone bleeped to tell me a colleague had DM&amp;rsquo;d me on Twitter. I made a mental note to check when I got home.
After a couple of hours spent building MetalBeard out of Lego I remembered and read it.
&amp;ldquo;Congratulations vExpert&amp;rdquo; it said. I checked the VMware blog and found this http://blogs.vmware.com/vmtn/2014/10/vexpert-2014-q3-announcement.html#src=vmw_so_vex_cneal_850
I was very pleased that my efforts evangelising around virtualisation and in particular VMware had been recognised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evils of snapshots!</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2011-07-21-the-evils-of-snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2011-07-21-the-evils-of-snapshots/</guid>
      <description>Been away from tech-blogging for a while now for a number of reasons, not least studying for vcp4.
On the way something came up at work which needed another blog post about it, despite many others doing the same!
Deleting snapshots, big ones especially, times out at 95% on VI3 VCenter 2 leaving you all panicked and squeaky bum time.
The simple summary is that coalescing a 200gb snap could take up to 6hrs :-( so be patient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supply and Demand : The Crazy Price of NICs</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2011-04-21-supply-and-demand-the-crazy-price-of-nics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2011-04-21-supply-and-demand-the-crazy-price-of-nics/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so I want to have my own ESXi host at home. Initially it may sound like a tall order but there are lots of good community sites out there describing how to do it and what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t.
www.vm-help.com has a very good HWCL on it compiled from user experience. So after trying and failing to install ESXi 4.1 I found on vm-help that my motherboard&amp;rsquo;s on-board NIC isn&amp;rsquo;t compatible as there are no drivers on the installation CD for it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
