<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Chris Neales Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Chris Neales Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ssh to Cygwin fails after Computer joins domain</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-06-10-cygwin-access-after-domainjoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-06-10-cygwin-access-after-domainjoin/</guid>
      <description>I was asked to look into an issue where ssh connections to a windows server running cygwin had started to fail after the computer joined an AD domain.
The user was running the scripts under a user local to that computer. They needed to use that to run scripts with the same user before AND after it joined the domain.
I checked the usual, updated a GPO to disable &amp;ldquo;Deny access to this computer from the network&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere VM Hotplug functionality confuses AD GPO and locks out non system drives</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-09-22-vsphere-vm-hotplug-functionality-confuses-ad-gpo-and-locks-out-non-system-drives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-09-22-vsphere-vm-hotplug-functionality-confuses-ad-gpo-and-locks-out-non-system-drives/</guid>
      <description>I was asked to look at an issue on a customer account where when a server VM, used as a XenApp Dynamic Desktop server is moved from Computers OU to the desired destination OU and gpupdate run then suddenly the D and E drives were inaccessible. They could be seen in &amp;ldquo;My Computer&amp;rdquo; and also in &amp;ldquo;Disk Management&amp;rdquo; but only listed as NTFS and no used/free space in My Computer, despite me having admin rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time waits for no man, or member server - The Importance of Time Synchronisation in Windows 2008 Domains</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2012-05-30-time-waits-for-no-man-or-member-server-the-importance-of-time-synchronisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2012-05-30-time-waits-for-no-man-or-member-server-the-importance-of-time-synchronisation/</guid>
      <description>I had built a Windows 2008 server from a custom SOE disc, all seemed well but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t register in DNS. I&amp;rsquo;d specified the name servers correctly and the server I&amp;rsquo;d built the week before had no issues registering in the same domain. This was a relatively new domain however and the server was pinging all the same and joined the domain without issue. I continued&amp;hellip;but then spotted that the SOE post build tasks had failed on Activating Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
