<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VCP on Chris Neales Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/vcp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VCP on Chris Neales Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/vcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading your HomeLab to Windows 10 &#43; VMware Workstation ??</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-07-06-upgrading-your-homelab-to-windows-10-vmware-workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-07-06-upgrading-your-homelab-to-windows-10-vmware-workstation/</guid>
      <description>I run my home lab on a PC running Windows 8.1 and VMware Workstation 10. The PC has an i7 with HT, 32GB RAM and an SSD.
I had to upgrade from Windows 7 as the Home Premium Edition only supported 16GB of RAM, which was irritating. I knew Windows 10 was coming but it&amp;rsquo;s End of July release date hadn&amp;rsquo;t been announced. So when it popped up offering me my &amp;ldquo;free upgrade&amp;rdquo; I accepted and am now dutifully waiting a couple of weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VCP5 Passed - Grasp The Nettle! (VCAP next)</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-06-25-vcp5-passed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-06-25-vcp5-passed/</guid>
      <description>I sat my VCP5-DCV last Monday (a week ago Monday now) and passed. 450/500 so I am quite chuffed.
It was a great relief as I had devoted lots of lunchtimes and evenings and late nights into silly times in the morning to it.
I was so relieved that I haven&amp;rsquo;t blogged or done anything out of work since!
I resumed things like going to the gym at lunch times (VCP5=Fat Nealo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VCP5 Lab Tweak - vApp/HA for one?</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-06-08-vcp5-lab-tweak-vappha-for-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-06-08-vcp5-lab-tweak-vappha-for-one/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using my little HP Microserver and it&amp;rsquo;s a beauty. However I do have to keep powering it on and then connecting with vi client to the host then powering on the VC Appliance, then the virtual ESXi hosts, you know the drill&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.
So how to get them to autostart. Well it&amp;rsquo;s a simple option and to my mind it looks like a mix of a vApp and HA :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VCP 5 - Objective 1.2 - Host/Configuration Tab (in essence!)</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-30-vcp-5-objective-1-2-hostconfiguration-tab-in-essence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-30-vcp-5-objective-1-2-hostconfiguration-tab-in-essence/</guid>
      <description>So here I&amp;rsquo;m going to describe what many possibly have done before, but it&amp;rsquo;s needed for the exam&amp;hellip;..so here goes.
Configure NTP on an ESXi host. Connect to the ESX/ESXi host using the vSphere Client. Click the Configuration tab. Click Time Configuration/Properties/Options/NTP Settings. Click Add. Enter the NTP Server name. Click OK. Click the General tab. Click Start automatically under Startup Policy. Click Start and click OK. Click OK to exit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VCP5 - Ditching Auto-Deploy!</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-26-vcp5-ditching-auto-deploy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-26-vcp5-ditching-auto-deploy/</guid>
      <description>After being an evangelist last week I&amp;rsquo;m now converting my Auto-Deploy ESXi hosts into Stateful installs and therefore ditching their wonderful ephemeralness!
Why? Well for the purpose of a small lab which I will have to rebuild at some point I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to configure the supporting architecture which would mainly be the host profiles and dhcp/pxe environment.
Also it&amp;rsquo;s another option and part of using Auto-Deploy. You can choose to apply a host-profile, once the machine has first booted into ESXi which will then write the install to disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VCP5 Auto Deploy - Much more than just an automated ESXi install</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-15-vcp5-auto-deploy-much-more-than-just-an-automated-esxi-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-15-vcp5-auto-deploy-much-more-than-just-an-automated-esxi-install/</guid>
      <description>Revision. It means to review (previously studied materials) according to dictionary.com
However as anyone who has ever studied for a tech exam knows it is usually the complete opposite! You know what you know. You work with it and click those options every day. BUT you know that the exam covers all the things you never use, some you may have never even looked at.
&amp;ldquo;Connecting windows to a Unix print server!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VCP 5 - The Journey Begins</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-10-vcp-5-the-journey-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-10-vcp-5-the-journey-begins/</guid>
      <description>I passed my VCP4 way back in 2011. Shortly after (very shortly!) those pesky developers released vSphere5. VMware generously allowed VCP4&amp;rsquo;s to upgrade by the end of Feb 2012. Whilst that was generous, at the time my brain was frazzled from VCP4 study, I&amp;rsquo;d only just really got stuck in to vSphere4 deployments and wanted to get hands-on v5 experience before I sat the VCP5 exam.
Time passed. VCP split into VCP-DCV, VCP-Cloud, VCP-DT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VTSP - VMWare Certification and Accreditation...not mutually exclusive!</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2011-08-15-vtsp-vmware-certification-and-accreditation-not-mutually-exclusive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2011-08-15-vtsp-vmware-certification-and-accreditation-not-mutually-exclusive/</guid>
      <description>Morning all,
I sat my VCP4 a couple of weeks ago and managed to pass. It&amp;rsquo;s a tough exam and requires you to know about all aspects of VMWare&amp;rsquo;s offerings (but all detailed in the exam blueprint pdf!)
I&amp;rsquo;m not going to give you tips here as Scott Vessey&amp;rsquo;s blog invented that wheel and keeps it well maintained http://vmwaretraining.blogspot.com/ However through my company I did find out something interesting.
As we are a VMWare partner (and many of you who are working toward VCP are likely to be too, check with your manager or VMWare account manager) then you may have access to the VMWare Partner University.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
