<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exam on Chris Neales Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/exam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Exam on Chris Neales Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/exam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exam Experience - AZ-500 Microsoft Azure Security Technologies (Microsoft Certified Azure Security Engineer Associate)</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2020-02-11-az500examexperience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2020-02-11-az500examexperience/</guid>
      <description>The Broadest Blueprint yet - In Depth I sat the AZ-500 exam last week. I had set aside some time for study, arranged an exam voucher through work, booked it. All set. I spent a few nights watching some pre-recorded study sessions delivered by a colleague Dan Oliver which were great and covered all the material in the exam areas, in varying degrees of depth as they were 1-2hrs sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exam Experience - AZ-103 Microsoft Azure Administrator</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-08-12-az-103-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-08-12-az-103-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</guid>
      <description>NOW WITH LABS! - An Updated Exam and Exam Format I sat the AZ-103 exam at the end of July, blog post is a little late due to some family stuff, but back on it now. I missed the deadline to do the transition exam, but that wasn&#39;t a big problem as they had replaced the previous requirement of two exams to get Azure Administrator (AZ-100 + AZ-101) down to just one in AZ-103 This exam felt very familiar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exam Experience - AZ-302 Microsoft Azure Solutions Architect Certification Transition</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-03-28-az-302-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-03-28-az-302-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</guid>
      <description>NOW WITH LABS! - An Updated Exam and Exam Format I sat the AZ-302 exam on Tuesday. It has been updated since the Beta considerably. Many who took the beta felt that it wasn&#39;t Architect focussed but more developer focussed. Now whilst in this new brave cloud world you have to be part Admin/Pre-Sales/Architect and Developer, writing C# or node.js code in an Architect Exam didn&#39;t seem fair to me either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exam Experience - 70-533 Implementing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions - (Post Jan 2018 Updates)</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2018-03-06-exam-experience-70-533/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2018-03-06-exam-experience-70-533/</guid>
      <description>An Updated Exam and Exam Format I sat the 70-533 exam last Wednesday. It was the version after the Jan 2018 updates. That last bit is critical. Cloud moves fast and Microsoft published the exam 4 years ago. It was originally based around ASM, the white and blue GUI and a different set of PowerShell commands. It also had a number of other concepts which have been migrated over that time into Azure Resource Manager as a deployment method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VCIX-NV Exam Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-11-21-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-11-21-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</guid>
      <description>Last month I sat and passed the VCIX-NV exam. Driven, like a lot of others, by the impending retirement of the exam that keeps getting extended...more on that later. This is a post in two parts, first the exam experience, second a few pondering on VMware Education&amp;rsquo;s current trajectory.
The Day Itself Here in the UK there are only 3, I believe, VCAP accredited test centres. I hopped on a train across to Leeds, that ended up being delayed and I only had time for a coffee and sandiwch before having to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best VCAP Study Aid is another person&#39;s time &amp; help</title>
      <link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-01-02-best-vcap-study-aid-is-another-persons-time-effort/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-01-02-best-vcap-study-aid-is-another-persons-time-effort/</guid>
      <description>Like many I&amp;rsquo;m currently cramming for my VCAP-DCA.
The reason behind the cramming is that it&amp;rsquo;s on the 15th Jan and it&amp;rsquo;s DCA510 which has been retired so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t push it back despite not getting the voucher long ago or starting studying long ago enough.
That&amp;rsquo;s my excuses out of the way early.
So I could write my own blog posts breaking down the blueprint. Well that is useful to me, being able to explain something to a level where someone else can understand it is a good demonstration of your knowledge of something usually&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
