<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PaaS on Chris Neales Blog</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/paas/</link><description>Recent content in PaaS on Chris Neales Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/paas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exam Experience - AZ-500 Microsoft Azure Security Technologies (Microsoft Certified Azure Security Engineer Associate)</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2020-02-11-az500examexperience/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2020-02-11-az500examexperience/</guid><description>The Broadest Blueprint yet - In Depth I sat the AZ-500 exam last week. I had set aside some time for study, arranged an exam voucher through work, booked it. All set. I spent a few nights watching some pre-recorded study sessions delivered by a colleague Dan Oliver which were great and covered all the material in the exam areas, in varying degrees of depth as they were 1-2hrs sessions.</description></item><item><title>Exam Experience - AZ-103 Microsoft Azure Administrator</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-08-12-az-103-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-08-12-az-103-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</guid><description>NOW WITH LABS! - An Updated Exam and Exam Format I sat the AZ-103 exam at the end of July, blog post is a little late due to some family stuff, but back on it now. I missed the deadline to do the transition exam, but that wasn't a big problem as they had replaced the previous requirement of two exams to get Azure Administrator (AZ-100 + AZ-101) down to just one in AZ-103 This exam felt very familiar.</description></item><item><title>Exam Experience - AZ-302 Microsoft Azure Solutions Architect Certification Transition</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-03-28-az-302-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-03-28-az-302-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</guid><description>NOW WITH LABS! - An Updated Exam and Exam Format I sat the AZ-302 exam on Tuesday. It has been updated since the Beta considerably. Many who took the beta felt that it wasn't Architect focussed but more developer focussed. Now whilst in this new brave cloud world you have to be part Admin/Pre-Sales/Architect and Developer, writing C# or node.js code in an Architect Exam didn't seem fair to me either.</description></item></channel></rss>