<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Study on Chris Neales Blog</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/study/</link><description>Recent content in Study on Chris Neales Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/study/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exam Experience - AZ-500 Microsoft Azure Security Technologies (Microsoft Certified Azure Security Engineer Associate)</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2020-02-11-az500examexperience/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2020-02-11-az500examexperience/</guid><description>I spent a few nights watching some pre-recorded study sessions delivered by a colleague Dan Oliver which were great and covered all the material in the exam areas, in varying degrees of depth as they were 1-2hrs sessions.
It was watching these that reenforced my understanding that this was possibly the broadest area of Azure. It&amp;rsquo;s obvious that security affects all things.
With the popularity of DevOPs and now DevSecOPs, we should all know that &amp;ldquo;Security should be baked in from the start&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Exam Experience - AZ-103 Microsoft Azure Administrator</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-08-12-az-103-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-08-12-az-103-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</guid><description>This exam felt very familiar. The questions were not vastly changed from 70-533 which I sat last year, and the format was the same as AZ-302 in that the exam is divided into sections:
Traditional Multiple choice Scenario based multiple choice, where the same scenario will be offered for many questions and different solutions proposed. You have to answer if the proposed solution will meet the requirements Labs. Where you actually log in to an Azure Portal and do things.</description></item><item><title>Exam Experience - AZ-302 Microsoft Azure Solutions Architect Certification Transition</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-03-28-az-302-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-03-28-az-302-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s also due to retire at the end of June, so if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this now&amp;hellip;GET STUDYING! :-)
As usual the IaaS sections and IAM/AD/Security areas, which I have most background in were quite simple to absorb. Where I had to pay much more attention is around the PaaS/Serverless application space. So Web Apps, Functions, Batch, Event Grids etc.
This may be different for you, but where I am currently we&amp;rsquo;re still helping a lot of customers move from on-prem into cloud, so they haven&amp;rsquo;t expanded or transformed to start using PaaS services heavily.</description></item><item><title>Exam Experience - 70-533 Implementing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions - (Post Jan 2018 Updates)</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2018-03-06-exam-experience-70-533/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2018-03-06-exam-experience-70-533/</guid><description>It also had a number of other concepts which have been migrated over that time into Azure Resource Manager as a deployment method.
Initially that had me concerned as I came to Azure 12 months ago fresh onto ARM. It was new at first but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any ASM baggage. I saw the exam still had lots of ASM content when I looked into it last summer. But there have been TWO updates to the exam since then.</description></item><item><title>VCIX-NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-11-21-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-11-21-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>This is a post in two parts, first the exam experience, second a few pondering on VMware Education&amp;rsquo;s current trajectory.
The Day Itself Here in the UK there are only 3, I believe, VCAP accredited test centres. I hopped on a train across to Leeds, that ended up being delayed and I only had time for a coffee and sandiwch before having to get started. Moral here is give yourself plenty of time to get to your chosen test centre and if possible/affordable, go the night before.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading your HomeLab to Windows 10 + VMware Workstation ??</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-07-06-upgrading-your-homelab-to-windows-10-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-07-06-upgrading-your-homelab-to-windows-10-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>I run my home lab on a PC running Windows 8.1 and VMware Workstation 10. The PC has an i7 with HT, 32GB RAM and an SSD.
I had to upgrade from Windows 7 as the Home Premium Edition only supported 16GB of RAM, which was irritating. I knew Windows 10 was coming but it&amp;rsquo;s End of July release date hadn&amp;rsquo;t been announced. So when it popped up offering me my &amp;ldquo;free upgrade&amp;rdquo; I accepted and am now dutifully waiting a couple of weeks.</description></item><item><title>Best VCAP Study Aid is another person's time &amp; help</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-01-02-best-vcap-study-aid-is-another-persons-time-effort/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-01-02-best-vcap-study-aid-is-another-persons-time-effort/</guid><description>Like many I&amp;rsquo;m currently cramming for my VCAP-DCA.
The reason behind the cramming is that it&amp;rsquo;s on the 15th Jan and it&amp;rsquo;s DCA510 which has been retired so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t push it back despite not getting the voucher long ago or starting studying long ago enough.
That&amp;rsquo;s my excuses out of the way early.
So I could write my own blog posts breaking down the blueprint. Well that is useful to me, being able to explain something to a level where someone else can understand it is a good demonstration of your knowledge of something usually&amp;hellip;.</description></item><item><title>Getting Back on the Horse! (Destination VCAP5-DCA)</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-08-14-getting-back-on-the-horse-destination-vcap5-dca/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-08-14-getting-back-on-the-horse-destination-vcap5-dca/</guid><description>After passing my VCP, and subsequently falling back into the bad habit of not studying! I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get the
The point is&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;..IT&amp;rsquo;S BACK ON! I&amp;rsquo;ll be studying again and blurting out blogposts about the activity.
As always, step 1 is READ THE BLUEPRINT!
http://mylearn.vmware.com/mgrReg/plan.cfm?plan=47316&amp;amp;amp;ui=www_cert&amp;amp;amp;src=vmw_so_vex_cneal_850</description></item><item><title>VCP5 Auto Deploy - Much more than just an automated ESXi install</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-15-vcp5-auto-deploy-much-more-than-just-an-automated-esxi-install/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-15-vcp5-auto-deploy-much-more-than-just-an-automated-esxi-install/</guid><description>Revision. It means to review (previously studied materials) according to dictionary.com
However as anyone who has ever studied for a tech exam knows it is usually the complete opposite! You know what you know. You work with it and click those options every day. BUT you know that the exam covers all the things you never use, some you may have never even looked at.
&amp;ldquo;Connecting windows to a Unix print server!</description></item><item><title>VCP5 Objective 1.2 “Quickly” Deploying Using AutoDeploy - Take 2</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-14-vcp5-objective-1-2-quickly-deploying-using-autodeploy-take-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-14-vcp5-objective-1-2-quickly-deploying-using-autodeploy-take-2/</guid><description>So when last we spoke I had left Linux updating.
It was when I came to resume last night that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t track down the original article I had been following.
It was only when I found Marco Broeken&amp;rsquo;s blog &amp;ldquo;vSphere5 Auto-Deploy in 20 Steps&amp;rdquo;. This started straight away with the, now, blindingly obvious statement that the VCVA is a Linux box, therefore my Ubuntu box was a waste of space.</description></item><item><title>VCP5 - Objective 1.2 "Quickly" Deploying Using AutoDeploy (3hrs later!!! ;-)</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-12-vcp5-objective-1-2-quickly-deploying-using-autodeploy-3hrs-later/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-12-vcp5-objective-1-2-quickly-deploying-using-autodeploy-3hrs-later/</guid><description>So tonight&amp;rsquo;s revision was meant to be pretty quick. It is Game Of Thrones night after all!
Well no such luck. I powered on my Microserver host and the vCenter appliance fired up with it automatically. Nice!
Logged on to the web client and the fat client. I have been trying to alternate between the two to make sure I can spot any differences, or things you can&amp;rsquo;t do in one but can in the other.</description></item><item><title>VCP5 - Fixing SSL Cert on newly deployed vCenter Server Appliance after changing IP</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-11-vcp5-fixing-ssl-cert-on-newly-deployed-vcenter-server-appliance-after-changing-ip/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-11-vcp5-fixing-ssl-cert-on-newly-deployed-vcenter-server-appliance-after-changing-ip/</guid><description>So you deploy the VCA from the OVA. Easy peasy. Any monkey could do that!
You config it from the webpage. Things like changing the default password, general good practice etc.
&amp;hellip;.and obviously you change the IP to a static one.
Wait! Stop! You just broke the VCA. Well you sort of did. You changed the name but didn&amp;rsquo;t update the SSL cert that was generated when it was first built/configured.</description></item><item><title>VCP 5 - The Journey Begins</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-10-vcp-5-the-journey-begins/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-10-vcp-5-the-journey-begins/</guid><description>I passed my VCP4 way back in 2011. Shortly after (very shortly!) those pesky developers released vSphere5. VMware generously allowed VCP4&amp;rsquo;s to upgrade by the end of Feb 2012. Whilst that was generous, at the time my brain was frazzled from VCP4 study, I&amp;rsquo;d only just really got stuck in to vSphere4 deployments and wanted to get hands-on v5 experience before I sat the VCP5 exam.
Time passed. VCP split into VCP-DCV, VCP-Cloud, VCP-DT.</description></item><item><title>VCP5 - Me and my virtual history</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-10-vcp5-me-and-my-virtual-history/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-05-10-vcp5-me-and-my-virtual-history/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m 37, work at a global IT services company with big customers. When I started in 2005 my first project was helping deploy 10s of ESX hosts. Yes &amp;ldquo;ESX&amp;rdquo; v2.5 &amp;ldquo;Virtual Infrastructure&amp;rdquo; hosts and Virtual Center 1.something or other. It&amp;rsquo;s 9 years ago now but we had multiple farms of 7 hosts (I think) which had shared LUNs, and all ran training courses. Each training course was 6 VMs. Only 1 was unique as a citrix presentation server v4 front-end.</description></item></channel></rss>