<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Exam on Chris Neales Blog</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/exam/</link><description>Recent content in Exam on Chris Neales Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/exam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exam Experience - AZ-500 Microsoft Azure Security Technologies (Microsoft Certified Azure Security Engineer Associate)</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2020-02-11-az500examexperience/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2020-02-11-az500examexperience/</guid><description>I spent a few nights watching some pre-recorded study sessions delivered by a colleague Dan Oliver which were great and covered all the material in the exam areas, in varying degrees of depth as they were 1-2hrs sessions.
It was watching these that reenforced my understanding that this was possibly the broadest area of Azure. It&amp;rsquo;s obvious that security affects all things.
With the popularity of DevOPs and now DevSecOPs, we should all know that &amp;ldquo;Security should be baked in from the start&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Exam Experience - AZ-103 Microsoft Azure Administrator</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-08-12-az-103-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-08-12-az-103-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</guid><description>This exam felt very familiar. The questions were not vastly changed from 70-533 which I sat last year, and the format was the same as AZ-302 in that the exam is divided into sections:
Traditional Multiple choice Scenario based multiple choice, where the same scenario will be offered for many questions and different solutions proposed. You have to answer if the proposed solution will meet the requirements Labs. Where you actually log in to an Azure Portal and do things.</description></item><item><title>Exam Experience - AZ-302 Microsoft Azure Solutions Architect Certification Transition</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-03-28-az-302-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-03-28-az-302-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s also due to retire at the end of June, so if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this now&amp;hellip;GET STUDYING! :-)
As usual the IaaS sections and IAM/AD/Security areas, which I have most background in were quite simple to absorb. Where I had to pay much more attention is around the PaaS/Serverless application space. So Web Apps, Functions, Batch, Event Grids etc.
This may be different for you, but where I am currently we&amp;rsquo;re still helping a lot of customers move from on-prem into cloud, so they haven&amp;rsquo;t expanded or transformed to start using PaaS services heavily.</description></item><item><title>Exam Experience - 70-533 Implementing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions - (Post Jan 2018 Updates)</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2018-03-06-exam-experience-70-533/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2018-03-06-exam-experience-70-533/</guid><description>It also had a number of other concepts which have been migrated over that time into Azure Resource Manager as a deployment method.
Initially that had me concerned as I came to Azure 12 months ago fresh onto ARM. It was new at first but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any ASM baggage. I saw the exam still had lots of ASM content when I looked into it last summer. But there have been TWO updates to the exam since then.</description></item><item><title>VCIX-NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-11-21-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-11-21-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>This is a post in two parts, first the exam experience, second a few pondering on VMware Education&amp;rsquo;s current trajectory.
The Day Itself Here in the UK there are only 3, I believe, VCAP accredited test centres. I hopped on a train across to Leeds, that ended up being delayed and I only had time for a coffee and sandiwch before having to get started. Moral here is give yourself plenty of time to get to your chosen test centre and if possible/affordable, go the night before.</description></item><item><title>Best VCAP Study Aid is another person's time &amp; help</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-01-02-best-vcap-study-aid-is-another-persons-time-effort/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-01-02-best-vcap-study-aid-is-another-persons-time-effort/</guid><description>Like many I&amp;rsquo;m currently cramming for my VCAP-DCA.
The reason behind the cramming is that it&amp;rsquo;s on the 15th Jan and it&amp;rsquo;s DCA510 which has been retired so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t push it back despite not getting the voucher long ago or starting studying long ago enough.
That&amp;rsquo;s my excuses out of the way early.
So I could write my own blog posts breaking down the blueprint. Well that is useful to me, being able to explain something to a level where someone else can understand it is a good demonstration of your knowledge of something usually&amp;hellip;.</description></item></channel></rss>