<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vsphere on Chris Neales Blog</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/categories/vsphere/</link><description>Recent content in vsphere on Chris Neales Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.chrisneale.org/categories/vsphere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I am not a N00b! - Telling vCenter to stop showing you getting started pages!</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-10-06-iamnotan00b/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-10-06-iamnotan00b/</guid><description>I should have found this years ago.
Like most of you reading this I get bugged by vCenter presuming this is my first Rodeo, as they say.
Everytime you go to a new Datacentre/Cluster/Folder/VM* (Delete as appropriate) it gives me the Getting Started pages.
So today I found the off switches:
For C# Client
For the Web Client
Job done. You are now L33t @ vCenter</description></item><item><title>All hail the PSC - Long Live the appliance!</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-10-05-thepsc-ridesintotown-withcertificatesforall/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-10-05-thepsc-ridesintotown-withcertificatesforall/</guid><description>VMware started as a Type 2 Hypervisor for doing a bit of lab/development testing on.
They&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way since and even started chopping Windows out of the picture whenever possible. VCSA did a great job at removing not just vCenter but a number of the vSphere components like dump collector, log browser, syslog collector and auto deploy.
But to have a fully tidy and enterprise environment you needed certificates.</description></item><item><title>VMware News Roundup - Announcement-ageddon!!!</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-03-13-vmware-news-roundup-announcement-ageddon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-03-13-vmware-news-roundup-announcement-ageddon/</guid><description>There was armageddon, then snowmageddon and now announcementageddon.
Twitter is on fire with frantic retweeting and updates on what people are excited about on the VMware front. And there&amp;rsquo;s plenty to be excited about right now.
The biggest unsurprising but best bit is vSphere 6.0 goes GA. Now everyone can try long distance vmotion, VVols, 4vcpu Fault Tolerance, Instant Clone and more. Register for a trial and download below https://my.vmware.com/group/vmware/evalcenter?p=vsphere6#src=vmw_so_vex_cneal_850</description></item><item><title>vExpert - Why go for it?</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-10-07-vexpert-why-bother/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-10-07-vexpert-why-bother/</guid><description>I was driving home Friday night when my phone bleeped to tell me a colleague had DM&amp;rsquo;d me on Twitter. I made a mental note to check when I got home.
After a couple of hours spent building MetalBeard out of Lego I remembered and read it.
&amp;ldquo;Congratulations vExpert&amp;rdquo; it said. I checked the VMware blog and found this http://blogs.vmware.com/vmtn/2014/10/vexpert-2014-q3-announcement.html#src=vmw_so_vex_cneal_850
I was very pleased that my efforts evangelising around virtualisation and in particular VMware had been recognised.</description></item><item><title>Allowing automated installs of newer VMtools than the host version (Caveat for Trend Deep Security)</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-06-12-allowing-automated-installs-of-newer-vmtools-than-the-host-version-caveat-for-trend-deep-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2014-06-12-allowing-automated-installs-of-newer-vmtools-than-the-host-version-caveat-for-trend-deep-security/</guid><description>During a recent patching cycle VMtools across a set of VMs were updated to the latest version. This was to patch security vulnerabilities in the versions which were running to ensure the environment was as secure as possible for a PenTest which would go towards IL3 Accreditation.
Shavlik was good enough to oblige here and went out and patched lots of VMs with new VMtools automatically to the latest version.</description></item></channel></rss>