<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Study on Chris Neales Blog</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/categories/study/</link><description>Recent content in Study on Chris Neales Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.chrisneale.org/categories/study/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VCP-NV=EZ</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-08-16-vcp-nvez/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-08-16-vcp-nvez/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 2 weeks now since I sat and passed the VCP-NV. Straight after the exam I went on holiday and on coming back I got straight back into work.
My background is working with VMware since Esx 2.x in 2005. In a more structured and career focussed way since 2011 when I did a great project to deploy 4 vBlocks with Linked vCenters. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on various virtualisation deployments, upgrades, support incidents (the joys of being on-call) and even a brief foray into setting up a Hyper-V environment for one customer!</description></item><item><title>Training Resource Review - Pluralsight + Jason Nash's NSX Courses</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-04-08-training-resource-review-pluralsight-jason-nashs-nsx-courses/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-04-08-training-resource-review-pluralsight-jason-nashs-nsx-courses/</guid><description>In a recent change of tack to my learning plan I&amp;rsquo;ve moved from revising VCAP-DCA to VCP-NV. This has been driven by a need for work to be familiar with NSX and Multi-Hypervisor Virtualised Networking too.
I did a couple of the NSX Hands On Labs last October at VMworld but other than a few terms, and the fact some bits looked a lot like vShield from the vCloud Suite most of it had leaked out of my brain.</description></item><item><title>VMware News Roundup - Announcement-ageddon!!!</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-03-13-vmware-news-roundup-announcement-ageddon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-03-13-vmware-news-roundup-announcement-ageddon/</guid><description>There was armageddon, then snowmageddon and now announcementageddon.
Twitter is on fire with frantic retweeting and updates on what people are excited about on the VMware front. And there&amp;rsquo;s plenty to be excited about right now.
The biggest unsurprising but best bit is vSphere 6.0 goes GA. Now everyone can try long distance vmotion, VVols, 4vcpu Fault Tolerance, Instant Clone and more. Register for a trial and download below https://my.vmware.com/group/vmware/evalcenter?p=vsphere6#src=vmw_so_vex_cneal_850</description></item><item><title>VCAP-DCA510 Failing to pass doesn't mean failing to learn</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-01-22-vcap-dca510-failing-to-pass-doesnt-mean-failing-to-learn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2015-01-22-vcap-dca510-failing-to-pass-doesnt-mean-failing-to-learn/</guid><description>Last Thursday I got the early train to Leeds stationed myself in a coffee shop and proceeded to stuff coffee and pastries into my mouth and last minute vSphere knowledge into my brain.
I had obtained a voucher to book the exam last year. However I&amp;rsquo;d been seconded to a &amp;ldquo;Business Transformation&amp;rdquo; project. Whilst this was quite interesting it did cause my technical skills to atrophy. To cut a long story short I rescheduled the exam a couple of times.</description></item></channel></rss>