<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PowerShell on Chris Neales Blog</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/powershell/</link><description>Recent content in PowerShell on Chris Neales Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.chrisneale.org/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Powershell to retreive Alerts which use a specific Action Group</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2021-05-14-powershell-to-retreive-alerts-which-use-a-specific-action-group/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2021-05-14-powershell-to-retreive-alerts-which-use-a-specific-action-group/</guid><description>"Is this Action Group used by any alerts?" If you want to find out if an Action Group is used by any alerts (metric or Log) how do you do it? Two simple queries help here:
To check if any Metric alerts point to your Action Group, run
Get-AzMetricAlertRuleV2 | ?{$_.actions.ActionGroupId -like &amp;#39;YourActionGroupName&amp;#39;} To check if any Log Alerts (Known as Scheduled Query alerts since classic was retired) run</description></item><item><title>Powershell to retreive Azure VM Memory Size</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2020-04-27-powershell-to-retreive-azure-vm-memory-size/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2020-04-27-powershell-to-retreive-azure-vm-memory-size/</guid><description>"How much memory do my VMs have?" It seems like an obvious thing to ask. It seems reasonable to me....However without additional tooling, such as inventory or configuration management software, you can't easily get a list of Azure VMs and their memory sizes that you can manipulate. If you just run "get-azvm" then it returns a property of the vm which is a "HardwareProfile". This just has a sub property of the VM t-shirt size.</description></item><item><title>Exam Experience - AZ-500 Microsoft Azure Security Technologies (Microsoft Certified Azure Security Engineer Associate)</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2020-02-11-az500examexperience/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2020-02-11-az500examexperience/</guid><description>The Broadest Blueprint yet - In Depth I sat the AZ-500 exam last week. I had set aside some time for study, arranged an exam voucher through work, booked it. All set. I spent a few nights watching some pre-recorded study sessions delivered by a colleague Dan Oliver which were great and covered all the material in the exam areas, in varying degrees of depth as they were 1-2hrs sessions.</description></item><item><title>Get-Module AZ fails because Azure=Azerbaijan</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-10-28-get-module-az-fails-because-azureazerbaijan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-10-28-get-module-az-fails-because-azureazerbaijan/</guid><description>When is a Culture a Module? Including pre-req checks in your code is good practice&amp;hellip;.so you add it in.
In our Powershell scripts which require Azure Powershell cmdlets we have moved, as should anyone keeping abreast of releases, to Powershell Core.
But our checks to see if the Az Module is installed were giving mixed results.
Even though the commands all worked, Get-AzVM etc. the module check for &amp;ldquo;Az&amp;rdquo; returned nothing, blank, nada.</description></item><item><title>Exam Experience - AZ-103 Microsoft Azure Administrator</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-08-12-az-103-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-08-12-az-103-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</guid><description>NOW WITH LABS! - An Updated Exam and Exam Format I sat the AZ-103 exam at the end of July, blog post is a little late due to some family stuff, but back on it now. I missed the deadline to do the transition exam, but that wasn't a big problem as they had replaced the previous requirement of two exams to get Azure Administrator (AZ-100 + AZ-101) down to just one in AZ-103 This exam felt very familiar.</description></item><item><title>Azure Instance Metadata Service Usage Examples</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-05-10-azure-instance-metadata-service-101/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-05-10-azure-instance-metadata-service-101/</guid><description>What does Azure have that VMware never had? AKA What is the Azure Instance Metadata Service? There&amp;rsquo;s probably a ton of answers here. But the one I was angling for is &amp;ldquo;Which vCenter is my VM running on?&amp;rdquo;
Who&amp;rsquo;d be crazy enough to lose a VM? Well you&amp;rsquo;d be surprised in enterprise estates that have been running for 10 years and Sue who managed the VM farm just retired and moved to Cypus so you can&amp;rsquo;t get hold of her to ask&amp;hellip; Anyway, what I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about it more useful than just finding out where your VM is if you (or your script/code) only has access inside the VM.</description></item><item><title>Exam Experience - AZ-302 Microsoft Azure Solutions Architect Certification Transition</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-03-28-az-302-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2019-03-28-az-302-exam-experience-and-study-advice/</guid><description>NOW WITH LABS! - An Updated Exam and Exam Format I sat the AZ-302 exam on Tuesday. It has been updated since the Beta considerably. Many who took the beta felt that it wasn't Architect focussed but more developer focussed. Now whilst in this new brave cloud world you have to be part Admin/Pre-Sales/Architect and Developer, writing C# or node.js code in an Architect Exam didn't seem fair to me either.</description></item><item><title>Using the Azure Load Balancer in reverse to funnel all outgoing traffic via a single IP</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2018-07-16-azurelbasinternetgateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2018-07-16-azurelbasinternetgateway/</guid><description>An Odd Request This implementation started from a SAP team who said they wanted to replicate, in Azure, the AWS Internet Gateway functionality. In particular the option for all outbound traffic from VMs to route via a single outbound IP. As you may know even if your default Azure VM does not have a Public IP assigned to it, it can still access the internet for things like windows updates etc.</description></item><item><title>Exam Experience - 70-533 Implementing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions - (Post Jan 2018 Updates)</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2018-03-06-exam-experience-70-533/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2018-03-06-exam-experience-70-533/</guid><description>An Updated Exam and Exam Format I sat the 70-533 exam last Wednesday. It was the version after the Jan 2018 updates. That last bit is critical. Cloud moves fast and Microsoft published the exam 4 years ago. It was originally based around ASM, the white and blue GUI and a different set of PowerShell commands. It also had a number of other concepts which have been migrated over that time into Azure Resource Manager as a deployment method.</description></item><item><title>Gotcha when importing client certificates for Azure P2S VPN</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2017-10-17-gotcha-with-azure-p2s-vpn-certificates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2017-10-17-gotcha-with-azure-p2s-vpn-certificates/</guid><description>After waiting 30 minutes for my P2S VPN gateway to deploy in Azure I was obviously eager to get VPN-ing, who wouldn't be! I ran through the instructions to generate a self-signed Root Cert and a client cert from Microsoft on this page [https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/vpn-gateway/vpn-gateway-certificates-point-to-site](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/vpn-gateway/vpn-gateway-certificates-point-to-site) \*(Put a pin here, we'll come back to this) I'd imported the certs to my test client VM and the Client VPN setup exe ran ok and created a connection in "</description></item><item><title>Leveraging Keepass via Powershell-Part 2</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2017-03-14-keepassinpowershell-part2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2017-03-14-keepassinpowershell-part2/</guid><description>Last time round we did 3 things
Loaded the Keepass DLL/EXEs in so we could call their routines Created an Empty KeePass DB construnct to read an existing DB in to Read in an existing KeePass DB into the pointer created in Step #2 These are common tasks we will need to do multiple times....so??? Yep functions. If you want to see the detail flip back to Part-1 Expand this for details of Function Code Blocks Function Load-KPBinaries { Param ($PathToKeePassFolder) # Check if Keepass DLLs are already loaded If (!</description></item><item><title>Leveraging Keepass via Powershell to Keep Passwords Out of Scripts</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2017-02-06-leveragingkeepassinpowershell-part1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2017-02-06-leveragingkeepassinpowershell-part1/</guid><description>Passwords visible in scripts&amp;hellip;.just say that out loud. If that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make you itch with a compelling urge to take the author to one side and have seriously stern words with them, then feel free to move on to the next blog&amp;hellip;.but you&amp;rsquo;re a bad person!
It&amp;rsquo;s something no-one should have to see, but sometimes, for brevity it happens. Someone hard codes a password in a script/program &amp;ldquo;just to test&amp;rdquo;. Well it&amp;rsquo;s a bad habit to get in to.</description></item><item><title>PowerCLI running in a Docker Container on Photon OS in under 10 minutes</title><link>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-11-07-docker-powerclicore-sub10mins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.chrisneale.org/posts/2016-11-07-docker-powerclicore-sub10mins/</guid><description>I needed a utility VM to run a PowerCLI script as a scheduled task.
I set out to do this using Windows but stopped as VMware&amp;rsquo;s Geniuses had just released the PowerCLIcore Fling. This instantly made me think, smaller footprint, quicker to deploy, zero OS license cost&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;No Brainer really
To recreate this all you need is something to host your Photon VM. Standalone ESXi host or VMWorkstation.
Oh and a VCSA/ESXi to connect to (v5.</description></item></channel></rss>